mamabzz.com 2018-08-16

# Privacy Policy and Disclosure - Adventures of Mel

This privacy policy sets out how Adventures of Mel (website) uses and protects any information that you (user) give while using [AdventuresofMel.com](https://adventuresofmel.com/).

## Who we are

Adventures of Mel is a website and family-owned small business owned by Mel Lockcuff and her husband Dan Lockcuff, not a big hotshot company that’s looking to collect your data and use it for who knows what. We enjoy sharing recipes, cooking tips, outdoor adventures, and family travel experiences with you, our readers. That’s why this website exists. I run ads because it is a business, and ads help to both pay expenses and provide for my family.

Should we ask you to provide certain information by which you can be identified when using this website, then you can be assured that it will only be used in accordance with this privacy statement.

Adventures of Mel has the discretion to update this privacy policy at any time. When we do, we will revise the updated date at the bottom of this privacy policy. We encourage users to frequently check this page for any changes to stay informed about how we are helping to protect the personal information we collect. You acknowledge and agree that it is your responsibility to review this privacy policy periodically and become aware of modifications. This policy is effective from May 1, 2018.

## Your acceptance of these terms

By using this Site, you signify your acceptance of this policy and terms of service. If you do not agree to this policy, please do not use our site. Your continued use of the site following the posting of changes to this policy will be deemed your acceptance of those changes.

## What personal data we collect and why we collect it

Adventures of Mel may collect and use Users’ personal information, such as the following:

  * Name and email address and name that you voluntarily provide by leaving a comment or subscribing to our newsletter.
  * Demographic information, such as a postal code, preferences, and interests.
  * IP address from the location you visit this website (anonymized to prevent identifiable information from being shared).

Adventures of Mel may collect and use Users’ personal information for the following purposes:

  * To personalize user experience.
  * We may use information in the aggregate to understand how our Users as a group use the services and resources provided on our site.
  * To improve our site.
  * We may use feedback you provide to improve our products and services.
  * To run a giveaway, survey, or other site feature.
  * To send users information they agreed to receive about topics we think will be of interest to them.
  * To send periodic emails.
  * We may use your email address to respond to your inquiries, questions, and/or other requests. If User decides to opt-in to our mailing list, they will receive emails that may include company news, updates, related product or service information, etc. If at any time the User would like to unsubscribe from receiving future emails, we include detailed unsubscribe instructions at the bottom of each email, or User may contact us via email.

### Comments

When visitors leave comments on the site, we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: <https://automattic.com/privacy/>. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

### Cookies

A cookie is a piece of information that the computer that hosts our services gives to your browser when you access the services. As you access this site, the file is added and the cookie helps analyze web traffic or lets you know when you visit a particular site. Cookies allow web applications to respond to you as an individual. The web application can tailor its operations to your needs, likes, and dislikes by gathering and remembering information about your preferences.

We use traffic log cookies to identify which pages are being used. This helps us analyze data about web page traffic and improve our website in order to tailor it to customer needs. We only use this information for statistical analysis purposes, and then the data is removed from the system.

Overall, cookies help us provide you with a better website, by enabling us to monitor which pages you find useful and which you do not. A cookie in no way gives us access to your computer or any information about you, other than the data you choose to share with us.

You can choose to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. This may prevent you from taking full advantage of the website.

Additionally, the website may use third-party service providers to service various aspects of the website. Each third-party service provider’s use of your personal information is dictated by their respective privacy policies.

If you leave a comment on our site, you may opt-in to saving your name, email address, and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment.

### Embedded content from other websites

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

### Analytics

Adventures of Mel uses Google Analytics to track statistics regarding our audience and website traffic. No personally identifiable information is transferred from the website to Google Analytics. [For more information on Google’s Analytics privacy policies, please visit this site.](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/)

### Adventures of Mel currently uses the following third-party service providers:

Mailerlite – We use this service for email delivery and newsletters. We store your first name and email address for purposes of delivering such communications. Mailerlite also collects who opens emails when we send them, the IP address where you open it, and what links (if any) you click once you open it. Please refer to [Mailerlite’s privacy policy](https://www.mailerlite.com/privacy-policy) for more information.

Feedblitz – Feedblitz provides the RSS feed for this website. Reader, Browser, and Search Engine information is recorded, but no personal information is collected. Please refer to the [Feedblitz privacy policy](https://www.feedblitz.com/privacy) for more information.

Mediavine – Mediavine manages our ads, and all EU visitors must consent to cookies before any ads appear. If you decline the cookies, you will not receive targeted ads but will still be able to access the website. Please refer to [Mediavine’s privacy policy](https://www.mediavine.com/privacy-policy/) for more information.

Google Adsense – Some of the ads may be served by Google. Google’s use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to Users based on their visit to our Site and other sites on the Internet. DART uses “non personally identifiable information” and does NOT track personal information about you, such as your name, email address, physical address, etc. You may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the [Google ad and content network privacy policy](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html).

StrataByte – StrataByte hosts this website. To create a visible site, they must run cookies, but they do not collect any personally identifiable information. StrataByte also runs a backup of this site to ensure it remains available if technical issues arise. Please refer to [StrataByte’s privacy policy](https://stratabyte.io/privacy_policy/) for more information.

Akismet – We collect information about visitors who comment on sites that use our Akismet anti-spam service. The information we collect depends on how the User sets up Akismet for the site, but typically includes the commenter’s IP address, user agent, referrer, and site URL (along with other information directly provided by the commenter such as their name, username, email address, and the comment itself). Please refer to their [privacy policy](https://automattic.com/privacy/) for more information.

WP Recipe Maker – This is our recipe card plugin. When you use comment ratings, the rating you’ve given to a recipe is stored, along with the personal data WordPress core stores. A cookie that contains the rating is stored; this cookie is used as (one of the) measures to prevent rating spam. The IP address is also stored upon voting; this is used as (one of the) measures to prevent rating spam. Cookies are stored for 30 days. User submitted data is stored indefinitely in the local database.

### Influencer Networks

We do occasionally partner with brands and networks to work on sponsored campaigns. The brands or networks may include a tracking pixel or link that gathers your IP address and visit history to gauge the effectiveness of the campaign. We do not directly share any personal information with them that we may gather through other means.

Influencer networks we occasionally partner with include the following:

  * Activate
  * Ahalogy/Muse
  * Acorn Influence
  * Clever
  * Influence Central
  * Massive Sway
  * TapInfluence
  * The Motherhood

### Affiliate Networks

Adventures of Mel may engage in affiliate marketing, which is done by embedding tracking links into the website. If you click on a link for an affiliate partnership, a cookie will be placed on your browser to track any sales for purposes of commissions.

Adventures of Mel is a participant in various affiliate programs designed to provide a means for sites to earn advertising fees by advertising and links to online retailers.  As part of these programs, the website will post customized links, provided by the affiliates, to track the referrals to their website(s). These programs utilize cookies to track visits for the purposes of assigning commission on these sales.

All posts that contain affiliate links disclose this at the top of each post. You will also have the opportunity to opt out of cookie collection when you click on any affiliate link.

### Third Party Websites

Users may find advertising or other content on our site that link to the sites and services of our partners, suppliers, advertisers, sponsors, affiliates, licensors and other third parties. We do not control the content or links that appear on these sites and are not responsible for the practices employed by websites linked to or from our site. In addition, these sites or services, including their content and links, may be constantly changing. These sites and services may have their own privacy policies and customer service policies. Browsing and interaction on any other website, including websites which have a link to our site, is subject to that website’s own terms and policies.

## How long we retain your data

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely.This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

If you subscribe to our newsletter, your name and email address are retained indefinitely, or until you unsubscribe.

## What rights you have over your data

If you have left comments on this site, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. To do so, please contact us at [mel@adventuresofmel.com](mailto:mel@adventuresofmel.com).

Please note this does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

## Where we send your data

We do not sell, trade, or lease Users’ personal identification information to others, unless we have your permission or are required by law to do so. We may share generic aggregated demographic information not linked to any personal identification information regarding visitors and users with our business partners, trusted affiliates and advertisers for the purposes outlined above. We may use third party service providers to help us operate our business and the site or administer activities on our behalf, such as sending out newsletters or surveys. We may share your information with these third parties for those limited purposes provided that you have given us your permission.

Visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service.

Our ads are served and managed by Mediavine. Some of our advertisers occasionally serve you cookies, as well. We do not have control over cookies placed by advertisers. We may use advertising service vendors to help present advertisements on the website. These vendors may use cookies, web beacons, or similar technologies to serve you advertisements tailored to interests you have shown by browsing on this and other sites you have visited, to determine whether you have seen a particular advertisement before and to avoid sending you duplicate advertisements. In doing so, these vendors may collect non-personal data such as your browser type, your operating system, Web pages visited, time of visits, content viewed, ads viewed, and other clickstream data. The use of cookies, web beacons, or similar technologies by these advertising service vendors is subject to their own privacy policies, not ours, and Service Provider disclaims all liability in connection therewith.

## Additional information

### How we protect your data

At no time should you submit sensitive personal information to the Website. This includes your social security number, information regarding race or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious beliefs, health information, criminal background, or trade union memberships. If you elect to submit such information to us, it will be subject to this Privacy Policy.

We adopt appropriate data collection, storage and processing practices, and security measures to protect against unauthorized access, alteration, disclosure, or destruction of your personal information, transaction information, and data stored on our site.

### What data breach procedures we have in place

We are committed to ensuring that your information is secure. In order to prevent unauthorized access or disclosure, we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online.

We use safe protocols for communication and transferring data (such as HTTPS). We use anonymising and pseudonymising where suitable. We monitor our systems for possible vulnerabilities and attacks on an ongoing basis.

We do not create accounts for our users, which minimizes any data we collect or store.

Even though we try our best, we can not guarantee the security of information. However, we promise to notify suitable authorities of data breaches. We will also notify you if there is a threat to your rights or interests. We will do everything we reasonably can to prevent security breaches and to assist authorities should any breaches occur.

## Children’s Privacy

The website is aimed at adults, age 18 and older.We do not target anyone under the age of 18 with our services or content. We never knowingly collect any personally identifiable information from children under the age of 18, and no part of our website is structured to attract anyone under the age of 18. If a parent or guardian believes that the Website has personally identifiable information of a child under the age of 18 in its database, please contact us immediately at [mel@adventuresofmel.com](mailto:mel@adventuresofmel.com), and we will use our best efforts to promptly remove such information from our records.

## Contact Information

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this site, please contact us at the following:  
Adventures of Mel  

 **This privacy policy was last updated on May 31, 2018.**

##  **Disclosure  
**

This policy is valid from 1 September 2009.

This blog is a personal blog written and edited by Mel Lockcuff. For questions about this blog, please contact  Mel at [mel@adventuresofmel.com](mailto:mel@adventuresofmel.com).

Adventures of Mel sometimes accepts forms of paid advertising, sponsorship, paid insertions or other forms of compensation. We also participate in affiliate programs which means that if you click on an affiliate link, I will either be paid for referring you there or paid a commission if you make a purchase.

We are a participant in the Amazon Services LLC Associates Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for us to earn fees by linking to Amazon.com and affiliated sites.

This blog abides by word of mouth marketing standards. We believe in honesty of relationship, opinion, and identity. The compensation received may influence the advertising content, topics, or posts made in this blog. That content, advertising space, or post will be clearly identified as paid or sponsored content.

The owner of this blog is sometimes compensated to provide opinion on products, services, websites and various other topics. Even though the owner of this blog sometimes receives compensation for posts or advertisements, we always give our honest opinions, findings, beliefs, or experiences on those topics or products. The views and opinions expressed on this blog are purely the bloggers’ own. Any product claim, statistic, quote or other representation about a product or service should be verified with the manufacturer, provider, or party in question.

Anything you read on this blog, you read of your own free will. This blog is our own opinions/reactions/words, and Adventures of Mel/Mel Lockcuff will not be held liable for any errors, losses, or damages incurred from its use thereof. We do not seek to offer professional advice, so reading is done at your own risk. We are not responsible for advertisers’ actions; if you purchase a product from a site advertised here on Adventures of Mel, and there is a problem with said product, you must take action with that company to find a solution.

All material/written posts/personal photos on our blog may not be used, reprinted, or published without our written consent.

To get your own policy, go to [http://www.disclosurepolicy.org](http://disclosurepolicy.org/).

####  **Essential Oils Disclaimer**

The information shared on this blog is not intended to diagnose, treat, cure, or prevent any disease, and has not been evaluated by the FDA.

Please always check with your doctor/caregiver before using essential oils. I want your experience to be safe and enjoyable. I am not a doctor and will never recommend treatment or claim that oils can cure a disease. The information on this site is not intended or implied to be a substitute for professional medical advice, diagnosis, or treatment. Please confirm any information obtained from or through this web site with other sources, and review all information regarding any medical condition or treatment with your physician. Never disregard professional medical advice or delay seeking medical treatment because of something you have read on this website. This information is not intended to diagnose, treat, or cure any disease.

Take special care in researching your own needs and the needs of your family when considering the use of oils. Special precautions should be taken for those pregnant and nursing, as well as children. Trust your gut, do your own research, and never use an oil in a way which makes you feel uncomfortable.

If you ever have any questions, please feel free to email [mel@adventuresofmel.com](mailto:mel@adventuresofmel.com). Thank you!

####  **Giveaway Policy**

Giveaways are occasionally posted here on Adventures of Mel. Each giveaway is usually run for a period of 3 weeks or less, according to Mel’s discretion. Winners are selected via a random generator/platform and contacted via email. Once contacted, giveaway winners have up to 72 hours to respond to Mel’s email; if they do not respond within that timeframe, another winner will be chosen and notified.

Entrants for giveaways on Adventures of Mel must be 18 years of age or older. All giveaways end at 11:59 pm CST unless otherwise stated. Mel reserves the right to disqualify entrants, change the giveaway end date without notice, or make any changes to the giveaway.

Mel is not responsible for lost or damaged items in the mail/delivery service, but she will do her best to contact the company/brand on your behalf, so that a resolution may be found.
